(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] The solution to this challenge
will be in two parts.
First, we want to create a centralized store
as a single source of truth,
and then we bind the components to the store data
by calling the hook from every component
so we can subscribe to the state changes
and apply side effects.
So let's go to our app example.
So this is this to the list.
So we have here the root components
where we keep the state management
at the top level of the root components.
So instead what we want is to move the state management
in a separate location, which will be the store.
So let's do that.
First you want to make sure
that you install Zustand by running npm install zustand.
Next we're going to be ready to add
those lines of code in order to create a new store.
So let's go back to our example.
So that's going to be the final project.
And here I'm going to create store.
Here we go.
And we're going to use this functions to create the store.
And this one will expose in the callback function,
the set function, which is to update the state,
and we also need to read the state,
so we're going to have access to get as well.
So I'm going to simply name my store, useStore.
And in order to create this one,
we're going to actually move all this logic from here.
So all this logic to the store.
So let's do the same.
We're going to need to define a start variable
to define a list.
And another list, all a filter to indicate
the status of the list.
So it's either we display all the elements
or the active ones, or the completed ones.
And as for the list, list and all the differences that
we either display the full list or the list filtered
with the ones that are completed only.
So that's why we have all those states variables.
So let's go ahead and define here.
So store data, and we're going to have also filter
which will be a default value of all.
And here for the default value for list and all,
we're going to copy from the app components right here.
And that's going to be the initial state.
So we're going to replace here with items,
like so.
And let's do that right away, which is to export default
because we're going to need to use useStore outside of here.
Next we're going to define all the functions.
So first what we have is
that we want to be able to submit elements,
add to the list with submit with check,
which is to cross items of the list.
So let's do that.
I'm going to submit, that's going to be a function.
Next, we want to check items off the list,
to mark them as completed.
All the features archive to delete all the items
that are completed like so.
And we also have setFilter
And this will be to change the status of the list.
So in order to update actually the value of this setFilter
so let's implement these functions.
What we need here is to update the variables all in list.
So basically for this one we're going to have for submit,
we're going to have an object as a parameter
and we're going to have access to this function,
which is set which is going to return a callback function.
And with this we're going to be able to update the state,
the store data.
So we're going to merge this new item
with the list of items that we have, which is existing.
So that's going to be like so.
And we're going to do the same for all.
And actually it's going to be list.
Let me fix that.
And here to update all, it's going to be all.
And then we're going to merge with the new item.
Next for check, we're going to need to also first have access.
We're going to read from the state.
So it's going to be all.
And we're going to do that
with get and then access the value of all.
And with that, actually I'm going to copy from here
just to move the logic from here.
I'm going to take all of this and go here.
I'm going to paste this and I'm going to make an iteration
in order to update whichever item we are targeting.
So I will need to access the information
of the unique ID of the items that we're targeting.
And then after that I'm going to update the store data again.
I'm going to copy
and this time I'm going to update with the updated array.
And same for all.
Then you have archive.
And for this one, we need to access the data
that corresponds to all, but also list here as well.
We are going to update.
So let's grab this function already.
And I'm going to need to first make an iterations to filter
which is the same here logic.
So I'm going to copy these lines from the app components
and then move it to the store.
And here I'm going to update with the list.
It's going to be filtered, and here this will be all filtered.
Then for set filter, it's going to be quite simple.
I'm going to also update
with set and we want to update here, filter with options.
So I'm going to pass also, we're going to get something data
which is passed as arguments.
And we're going to update with the options.
So this is to update the list
just to tell like it's either active,
completed, or all to display the full list.
So that's it for the store.
So that's quite complete.
Next we're going to see how we can actually consume the data,
the store data.
And for that we're going to bind the components
to the store by calling this hook.
So let's just make sure here that you export default.
The next step to this solution will be to then add
to the scope of this app components.
And we want to refactor the whole thing.
We're going to replace the React API with zustand
so we can bind every component to the state
instead of passing the data with the props.
So let's do that next.